ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
桃小兔吃冰棒
翻译
木浅薰
showeryhe
翻译
煮粥达人
电脑团
翻译
静妹粒  累
冬麟  某羽
时间轴
chance-coco  兜兜兜爹  念念
电脑狂人
第三季
第四集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
周一
头疼
恶心
周二
左手发抖
双手发抖
头疼
周三
恶心/没有食欲
或许可以单飞  我喜欢道格  但我们意见不一  晚饭后跟黛安商量一下
周四
恶心
你的代码到处都在循环
Your code loops all over the place.
毫无结构可言  就没有人能维护
It's not structured. It's not maintainable by anyone.
-我不同意  -还有重入分叉
- I disagree. - There are reentrant forks,
根本看不出哪一条是调用函数
no way of knowing which branch invoked a function.
C++都不这么用了
We don't do that in C++.
已经被C++淘汰了
It's officially deprecated in the language.
我可以维护  每一样都有自己的状态标记
I can maintain it. There are condition flags for everything.
也没有无效代码
There's no one-way arrow.
这就是你想干的事吗
Is that what you want to do?
专门当这堆废物的修理工
Be the code grunt for this sick piece of choss?
道格  镇定
Dougie, chill.
我的人会做逻辑流程图  我来标记
My guys will flow chart it. I'll write out the flags...
我相信你可以
I'm sure you will.
你的流程图就能绕死人  根本一团乱麻
The flow chart would strangle us. It's a mess.
而且什么叫你的人
And what do you mean your guys?
它很快  而且能用
It's fast and it fits.
它已经没必要了
It's no longer necessary.
道格  是我们买了你的公司
Doug, we bought your company.
你得适应我们的编程语言
You should adapt to our programming language.
我知道重编很烦人
I know it sucks to be rewritten.
毫无道理可言
It doesn't make sense.
简直是要让跑车改装成马车
It's like asking a race car to adapt to a covered wagon.
-真文艺  -也许我们都应该
- Poetic. - Maybe we should all try to,
放下自负看问题
you know, take our egos out of it.
我很乐意放下我的自负
Well, my ego would love to have a good night's sleep,
但很不幸  我还得要它改写你的代码
but sadly it has to rewrite your code first.
天哪
Yikes.
黛安  我很抱歉
Diane, I am so sorry.
等扎到人就不好玩了
It's all fun and games till someone gets stabbed in the cheek.
我只是来看看
I'm just here to observe.
好吧
Okay, well...
我想我们已经解决了分歧
I think we're all on the same page now.
没错  很接近了
Definitely. Um, we're really close.
也许能用上这个
Maybe this'll help.
这是整合路径图
It's an integration road map.
我们认为你建立穆特尼的方式很棒
Look, we think the way you created Mutiny was brilliant.
原始的代码块确实很有创意
The original block of code was truly innovative.
但是
Mm-hmm, but?
但跟我们跳蚤市场的代码不合
It doesn't play nice with our SwapMeet code.
如果你那块稍加改动
If you make some changes to that block
我们也调整一下我们的C++
and we make some changes to our C++...
全是错误  凭原始代码
It's a bug factory. The old code makes it impossible
无法跟踪我们的重入循环
to keep track of the reentrant looping.
但我不需要面向对象的语言  好吧
But I don't need the object-oriented language, okay?
我靠脑子就能追踪循环
I can keep track of the looping in my head.
我懂了  你就那么牛
Oh, I get it. You're that good.
没错  就那么牛  你不是吗
Yeah, I am. Aren't you?
正四下张望呢  然后
...looking all around and then
他从拖车侧面走出来
he came around the side of the trailer there.
我发誓  他说
And I swear to God, he goes,
"老兄  那不是熊  那是你前妻"
"Man, that ain't no bear. That's your ex-wife."
之前的事都是她干的
She was just doing the whole thing.
你们没约吗
Oh, you surprised to see her?
没约
Yeah.
别了  朋友
Adios, amiga.
好啊
Hey there.
来吧  请  你先
Here, go ahead. After you.
谢谢
Thank you.
祝好  女士们
Good day, ladies.
真是惊喜呢
Well, this is a nice surprise.
我刚好在附近
I was in the neighborhood.
跟跳蚤市场的人处得如何
So, how's it going with the SwapMeet guys?
挺好
Good.
你电话上也是这么说
You keep telling me that on the phone
但声音里都透着不确定
with that same not-so-sure thing you do with your voice.
什么不确定
What not-so-sure thing?
我刚刚旁观了他们的项目会
Anyway, I just popped into their project meeting.
闹得很僵
The vibe was pretty hostile.
你怎么不告诉我呢
Why haven't you told me?
因为正在做嘛
Well, it's a work in progress.
-唐娜  -我知道
- Donna. - I know.
卡梅跟他们还没磨合好
Cam isn't comfortable with the guys yet,
我会处理的
and I'm working on it.
-你打算怎么处理  -那个
- How are you working on it? - Well--
我的意思是  应该我们一起来处理
My point is, we should be working on it.
如果有问题  我们就该解决它
If there are issues, we need to air them out.
否则不满情绪积累恶化
Otherwise resentment festers
一切都会完蛋
and the whole thing starts to rot.
好吧  不如这样
All right, how about this?
今晚我们一起吃饭
We could all go to dinner tonight,
喝点葡萄酒  聊聊清楚
have some wine, talk things through.
-我喜欢葡萄酒  -很好
- I do like wine. - Great.
但今晚不行
But I can't do tonight.
我要去参加个慈善晚会
I've got tickets to a charity thing,
为拯救海湾募捐
a fundraiser for Save the Bay.
-听上去...  -很糟
- Oh, that sounds-- - Terrible.
我本来想说很有爱
I was gonna say lovely.
我的同伴刚取消了  我可以带个伴儿
My date just cancelled and I have a plus one.
我可以问问戈登
I could check with Gordon,
看看他今晚能不能照看孩子们
see if he could watch the girls tonight.
不是
No, um...
我是想邀请约翰·博斯沃思
I was thinking about John Bosworth.
这样啊...
I mean...
真的吗
really?
"那不是熊  是我前妻"
"Man, that ain't no bear. That's my ex-wife."
会有一堆硅谷的大人物在那儿
You know, there'll be a whole slew of Valley big shots there.
对于约翰来说是个建立商业关系的好机会
It's a great opportunity for John to make some business connections.
当然
Sure.
但是
But...
没人叫他约翰
nobody calls him John.
我就这么叫
I do.
好了  各位
All right, guys.
各位
Guys.
各位  安静  安静
Guys, please, please!
闭嘴  小屁孩
Yo, shut up, kid!
好了  我知道我们开局不顺
All right, I know we've gotten off to a rough start,
为此我很抱歉
and I'm sorry about that.
这话太轻描淡写了
That's the understatement of the century.
自从卡梅接手当主程序员后
We're in a bit of a holding pattern
我们就基本停滞不前
ever since Cam took over for our lead coder.
-她就是仿生人  -你什么都不懂
- Yeah, that was gynoid. - You don't know jack about it.
但我们要以此为契机
But we're gonna use this as an opportunity.
我们已成功地绘制了两个系统的流程图
Now, I know we've had some success flowcharting the two systems.
我们的组织培训模式进展如何
How are we doing with our organizational training objectives?
你是说结伴体系吗
Oh, you mean the buddy system?
培训这些蠢蛋就是噩梦
It's a nightmare trying to train these jokers.
他们就不停抱怨C++
All they want to do is bitch about C++.
C++
C++.
他就成天跟着我  做他那套愚蠢的动作
He just follows me around all day doing this idiotic routine.
-C++  -卡尔  他是你带的实习生
- C++. - Carl, he's your trainee, okay?
-我才不管  -卡尔主人  我被预设成
- I don't care. - Master Carl, I've been programmed
-观察你的一举一动  -好吧
- to observe your every move... - Okay.
好通过你不甚完美的言行
So I may learn from your flawed behavior
学习如何当人类
what it is to be human.
闭嘴  闭嘴
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
这一点都不好笑
He's not even funny.
博迪  别再针对他了
Bodie, stop antagonizing him, okay?
-哔哔  -你给我滚
- Beep-boop-beep. - Get out of my face!
干掉这群混蛋
Let's kill these a-holes!
冷静
Calm down!
我去  你没事吧
Oh, shit. You okay?
大家都坐下
Everyone, sit down.
到底怎么
What the f--?
看到没  真是个好房子
You see? It is just so charming.
线脚都是原始的
It has all the original molding.
还有土生土长的霉菌
And all the original mold.
后院也很好  很适合烧烤
And the backyard is adorable. It's perfect for barbecues.
你听到了吗
Oh, did you hear that?
那我让你和你的  朋友
Okay, why don't I give you and your, uh, friend
谈一下吧
a minute to talk?
谢谢
Thanks.
她以为我俩是一对
She thinks we're a couple.
你不是我的菜
You're not my type.
这地方有自己的特点
Yeah, this place has character.
不是千篇一律的样子
This isn't a generic box.
不  穆特尼的房子才有特点
No, the Mutiny house had character.
这里只是古怪
This place is just quaint.
我们看的每套房子你都讨厌
You've hated every place we've seen.
那又怎样  我很挑的
So? I'm picky.
每个地方的感觉都不对
And nothing feels right.
是因为房子还是其他什么事
Is this about the house or is this something else?
是因为一号和二号
It's Thing One and Thing Two.
天哪  我受不了他俩
God, I can't stand them.
尤其是大块头那个  傲慢的兄弟会成员
Especially the bigger Thing, this arrogant frat boy.
小的那个还凑合
The smaller Thing's not so bad.
你知道他们的名字
You know their names.
是  半斤和八两
Yes, Tweedledee and Tweedledum.
哈克和杰克  庸人和庸才
Heckle and Jeckle. Frick and Frack.
我懂了  但他们想帮忙的
I get it. But they want to be useful.
怎么帮
By what?
把所有东西都转换成C++吗
Translating everything into C++?
唐娜  如果我知道计划是这样
Donna, if I knew that was the plan,
我不会签字同意的
I wouldn't have signed on.
但我们已经签了
But we did sign on.
他们俩跟公司有两年的合约
The guys are under a two-year contract
占有公司股份  我们跟他们绑在一起了
with a piece of the company. We married them.
我们得趁恶化
We have to sit down and talk it out
完蛋前  坐下来谈清楚
before the whole thing festers and rots.
-明晚我们一起吃饭  -什么
- We're having dinner tomorrow night. - What?
真是个可怕的主意  谁提议的
That's a horrible idea. Who suggested that?
我
I did.
太好了
Oh, great.
你这只是通知我
And so now you're just informing me.
看到了吗  已经有家的感觉了
See? It already feels like home.
麦克米伦实用网络本就是个出发点
MacMillan Utility was always intended to be a jumping-off point.
没错  关键在于转变
Totally. It's all about transformation.
许多公司从一件事起步
Many companies start doing one thing
之后改变方向
and then change direction.
如果我们能找到正确的方向
If we can just find the right vector.
那我们的免费软件就能一直免费
Then our freeware can stay free.
路由器技术很有前景
Router tech is promising.
思科在这方面已经走在很前面了
Ah, Cisco's already way ahead on that one.
三维图形  人工智能
Uh, 3-D graphics. Uh, AI.
第五代系统
5th gen systems.
那耗费巨大且将毫无结果
It's a billion-dollar road to nowhere.
一年就得完
I give it a year.
费尔柴德之前做照相机
Fairchild made cameras.
现在他们做半导体
Now they make semiconductors.
科乐早期叫康涅狄格州皮革公司
Coleco was the Connecticut Leather Company.
现在他们做电子游戏
Now they make video games.
穆特尼作为游戏公司起步
Yeah, and Mutiny started as a games company.
-闭嘴  -抱歉
- Shut up. - Sorry,
能参与你的思考过程我太激动了
I'm just so stoked to be a part of your process.
-加上咖啡因  -不  我是说安静
- Plus the caffeine... - No, I mean be quiet.
闭嘴
Now.
拜托
Please.
好吧
Okay.
我们来回顾那五个最好的主意
Let's circle the five best ideas.
等等  你干什么呢  伙计
Wait, what-- what are you doing, man?
我们花了好几周研究出来的
We spent weeks on that.
这里可有不少好点子啊
There's some good stuff there.
"好"是"伟大"的敌人
Good is the enemy of great.
要是有什么值得深讨的点子
If anything's worth pursuing,
我们明天照样记得起来
we'll remember it tomorrow.
BGM: Beyond Belief
进来...
Come in...
如果你非得进来
if you must.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk for a minute?
好吧
I guess.
我知道我们关系一开始就不怎么好
Look, I know we got off on the wrong foot.
我们的目标是一致的  对吧
I mean, we all want the same thing, right?
是的
Yeah.
也许我们...
Maybe we...
进展得太快了
got into this too quickly,
但是没错  我们既然都在一起了
but, yeah, let's-- we're in it now, so...
如果你觉得太快了
If you think it was too quick,
那可是多亏了你的博斯
you have your man Bos to thank.
-他逼我们接受协议的  -真的吗
- He strong-armed us into taking the deal. - Really?
因为我可是听说你
'Cause I heard that you
-和格雷格故意虚报  -是克雷格
- and Greg misrepresented... - It's Craig.
公司价值  想骗我们多花钱
...the value of your company to lure us into overpaying.
你怎么回事
What's your deal?
你为什么这么难与人合作
Why do you have such a hard time playing with others?
你生来就是这样  还是你的哪个废柴前男友
Were you born this way or did some loser ex-boyfriend
把你变成了仇男的贱人
turn you into a man-hating bitch?
什么事
What?
凯瑟琳  是你吗
Catherine? Is that you?
-是的  -我是伦恩
- Yes. - It's Len.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没什么  只是...抱歉打扰你工作了
Nothing, just-- sorry to call you at work.
我想告诉你你妈妈...
I wanted to let you know your mom...
怎么了
What?
你妈妈和我准备卖房子
Your mom and I are selling the house.
在迈阿密郊区买个小公寓
Bought a little condo outside of Miami.
我们得把车库里的那些破烂都处理掉
We gotta get rid of all that crap in the garage.
你想要你爸的东西吗
Do-- do you want your dad's stuff?
你妈妈特意为你留的  但是  要去迈阿密嘛
Your mom saved it for you, but, you know, Miami.
我们准备把所有剩的东西趁国庆节周末卖掉
We're gonna sell everything that's left over 4th of July weekend.
我希望你能来看看
I was hoping you might come and take a look,
跟你妈妈问个好
say hello to your mother.
情况已经不一样了
It's not like it used to be.
她现在好多了
She's much better now.
那为什么她不打给我
then why didn't she call?
希望你在那儿一切顺利
I hope you're doing well out there.
我会告诉你妈我们聊过了
I'll let your mom know that we talked.
你必须得道歉
You need to apologize.
你只要说一句"对不起"就行了
All you have to do is say, "I'm sorry," That's it.
我要道多少次歉才行
How many times have I gotta try?
-天啊  -等下  道格
- God. - Wait, Doug!
你们怎么了
Hey, what was that about?
只是我们梦幻的合作关系的日常摩擦
Oh, just the usual ups and downs of a magical partnership.
你待到好晚啊
You're here late.
不过你好像总是很晚才走
But then you're probably always here late.
你是在说我没有私生活吗
Are you implying that I don't have a life?
是的
Yes.
可以说道格和我风格不同
You could say that Doug and I have different styles.
可不是
No shit.
他刚进我办公室说我是个贱人
He just walked into my office and called me a bitch.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
听着  我们都很高兴能成为穆特尼的一员
Look, we're really excited to be part of Mutiny.
只是跳蚤市场是我们的心血
It's just SwapMeet was our baby.
我觉得道格依然在为出售而难过
I think Doug still feels down about having to sell.
但那不是借口
But that's no excuse.
你想看点很酷的东西吗
You want to see something cool?
是尸体吗
Is it a dead body?
如果道格还在的话
Only if Doug's still here.
你确定这样做好吗
You sure this is okay?
他不会介意的
He won't mind.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
问吧
Okay.
为什么你不愿改动原始的PL/M代码块
Why won't you change that original block of PL/M?
那是仅剩的我自己写的程序
It's the only piece left that I wrote by myself.
我一个人在卧室里做的
Alone in my bedroom, just me.
那时候只有我自己
Back when this whole place was just me.
所有时序都是我亲手完成的
I did all the timings by hand,
我用检查循环检查了
I checked the status on every buffer
每一个缓冲和每一次键盘输入的状态
and every keystroke every time, all with check loops.
很快而且...
It was fast and it was...
很美妙
Beautiful.
它很美妙
It is beautiful.
是啊
Yeah.
你要我说什么呢
And what do you want me to say?
我为这里感到骄傲
I-- I'm proud of this place.
但那个时候  都没人知道
But back then, it was this secret.
只有我自己
It was all mine.
那就别改它了
Then we should leave it alone.
我刚刚接到了十分奇怪的电话
Just got the weirdest phone call.
我继父
My stepfather.
他和我妈要搬去佛罗里达
I guess he and my mom are moving to Florida.
他们要把我爸的东西都卖掉
They're selling all my dad's stuff.
他去世时我九岁
He died when I was nine.
我去
Shit.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
他有辆摩托车
Just he had this motorcycle...
一辆旧哈雷平底锅
an old Panhead Harley.
他经常开着它送我去上学
Oh, he used to ride me to school on it.
我戴着顶巨大的头盔
I'd show up to kindergarten with this, like,
去幼儿园
gigantic helmet.
看上去肯定很傻  但是...
I'm sure it looked ridiculous, but it was--
却让我觉得...
it just felt so...
你应该去把车拿回来
You should go get the bike.
你没考虑过自己办个公司吗
Have you ever considered a solo business venture?
任天堂游戏机不是给琼妮的吗
Wasn't the Nintendo system supposed to be for Joanie?
不  是给全家的
No, it was a family present.
反正  经过了今天的吵闹  我得放松一下
Anyways, I had to unwind after that brawl today.
我真拿那些家伙没办法
I honestly don't know what to do about those guys.
卡迪夫的活儿不好干
Cardiff had its challenges,
但还从没有人打我的耳朵
but no one ever punched me in the ear.
是啊  你已经不在卡迪夫了
Yeah, well, you're not at Cardiff anymore.
这就是答案
There's your answer.
带他们出去  一个个毙掉
Just take the guys out back and shoot 'em.
他从拖车侧面走出来
Well, he comes around the side of the trailer,
然后说  "老兄  那不是熊  是你前妻"
and he goes, "Man, that ain't a bear. That's your ex-wife."
看到了吗  谢谢  谢谢
See? Thank you, thank you.
太疯狂了
Man, it was crazy, man.
我不知道她在那里待了多久了
And I don't know how long she stayed there.
她在那里一整夜了
She was there all night,
都有点冻僵了
just sort of frozen in place.
可怜虫
The poor bastard...
别走
Don't move.
乔·麦克米伦
Joe MacMillan.
当然
Of course.
黛安·古德
Diane Gould.
我们从未正式见过面  真是有趣
Funny that we've never officially met.
但我可是知道你
But I'm certainly aware of you.
阿马多·古德·吉尔森  我欣赏你们的商业模式
Amador Gould Gilson. I admire your business model.
精简的技术投资组合
Small, intelligent investment portfolio.
可以称之为精品店
I guess you could call that boutique.
规模不是一切  对吧
Well, size isn't everything, right?
我听说你帮穆特尼收购了跳蚤市场
I hear you facilitated the SwapMeet acquisition at Mutiny.
恭喜
Congrats.
我们对此很激动
We're very excited about it.
我很惊讶卡梅伦·豪伊能愿意
I'm surprised Cameron Howe wanted to play ball
跟其他公司共事
with another company.
她肯定心情很好
She must be in a good place.
打扰了  我能...
Excuse me. Can I, um--
-跟你说句话吗  -当然
- can I borrow you for a sec? - Yeah.
很高兴终于认识你了
It's great to finally meet you.
我也是
Mm, you as well.
我上哪去弄个那玩意
How do I get one of these?
赚更多钱
Make more money.
这就要说到我们的小问题了
Which brings us to our little problem.
你听过这个人吗  托弗·埃里克森
You heard of this individual, Topher Erickson?
没印象
Does not ring a bell.
他爸爸是卡尔·埃里克森
His father's Cal Erickson,
通用原子的高级副总
senior vice president of General Atomics.
好吧
Okay.
他好像参加过你的一个派对
Well, apparently he was at one of your parties
在派对上摄入了大量可卡因
and indulged in a copious amount of cocaine.
然后开着他爸给他的18岁生日礼物
And then grabbed someone and went off on a little joyride
一辆全新的法拉利带人去兜风
in the brand-new Ferrari his father procured for his 18th birthday.
哪个混蛋会花六万块买意大利车
What kind of jerk spends 60 grand and buys Italian?
可这个混蛋
Yeah, well, this particular jerk
是你四分之一的收入
funds about a quarter of your business.
好吧
Okay.
而你需要这种无聊的客户
And it's boring old contractor clients like that
来支持你的软件实验
that float your little software experiments.
我去找人聊聊
I'm gonna mingle.
安排一下  我会大事化小
Set something up. I'll do damage control.
很好
Good.
你好
Hi there.
真"友好"
Friendly fella.
不是所有人都有你那南方人的热情
Well, we can't all have your Southern charm.
感谢你在我孙子出生时打来问候
I want to thank you for calling me when my grandson was born.
是你打的吧
That was you, right?
是啊  神秘的乔·麦克米伦
Oh, sure. Joe MacMillan, man of mystery.
能与老朋友叙叙旧真好
Yeah, it's always good to hear from an old... friend.
你也挺会交新朋友的
Well, you seem to be doing just fine making new friends.
古德女士只是个生意伙伴
Oh, Miss Gould is just a business associate.
不  我是说这里所有人
Oh, no, I mean everyone here.
他们都很喜欢你
They're lapping you up.
拿德州范儿做文章是个好主意
It's a good call, playing up the Texas thing.
大家就喜欢看表演
People love a performance.
你也挺会演的啊
It looks like you're in a performance of your own, huh?
更像是独角戏
More of a one-man show kind of thing.
是的  我就是独角戏大师
Yeah, I'm a regular Spalding Gray.
我还要去招呼人
I left someone hanging.
保重
Be well.
太好了  你还在这儿
Oh, good, you're still here.
我还担心你被老朋友乔·麦克米伦绑架了呢
I was worried you got kidnapped by that old pal Joe MacMillan.
-要续杯吗  -好的  谢谢
- Can I top you off? - Yes, please.
你今晚轰动全场啊
You certainly made a splash tonight.
怎么说
How so?
你是派对的焦点
You're the life of the party.
大家都喜欢你
Everybody loves you.
这话只跟你说  我告诉唐娜
Between you and me, I told Donna
我是为公事邀你来
I was inviting you for business.
但其实  我就是不想一个人来
But really, I just didn't feel like flying solo,
尤其在这种情况下
you know, under the circumstances?
很高兴能帮忙
Glad I could be of service.
多疯狂啊
Isn't that crazy?
你跟一个人建立了一段生活  一起养孩子
That you can build a life with someone, raise kids,
从二十多一直到四十过半都在一起
spend your 20s, your 30s, half your damn 40s together,
最终却毫无感觉了
and in the end feel nothing?
怎么可能啊
How is that possible?
我不知道
I don't know.
要抽根烟吗
Would you like a cigarette?
不了
No.
不用
No, I'm good.
我不知怎么失去了对香烟的胃口
Somewhere along the line, I lost my taste for tobacco.
还有香槟酒
And champagne.
派对
Parties.
我跟律师说  我不想飞过来
I told my lawyer I didn't want to fly up here
马上保托弗出去
and bail Topher out right away.
让他冷静一下吧
Let him cool his heels for a while,
好好想想自己的行为
reflect upon his actions.
再说  我也不太喜欢旧金山
Plus, SF's not my cup of tea.
离开拉荷亚肯定很不舍
It must be hard to leave La Jolla.
我喜欢德尔马  完美混合了
I love Del Mar. It's got the perfect mix of
沙岸浪区和一片片的礁石
sand bottom beach breaks and patchy reefs.
很容易找到合适自己的浪
It's, uh-- it's very easy to find a wave you can call your own.
我一向羡慕冲浪的
I've always envied surfers.
我们在科罗纳多岛跟海军合作
We do a little naval work out at Coronado Island.
那些海上的家伙
Those bastards offshore
好像什么都不在乎
look like they don't have a care in the world
我却困在办公室里担心包交换
while I'm stuck to my seat worrying about packet switching
和电脑病毒  真是的
and computer viruses, thank you very much.
包交换
Packet switching?
-国防部的吗  -嗯  没什么意思
- Is that with the DoD? - Yeah, nothing sexy.
就是搬运一堆电子箱子
Just moving a bunch of electronic boxes around.
系统慢得要死
System's so damn clunky,
他们打算全部重做
they're gonna overhaul the whole thing.
一听就是麻烦
Ugh, sounds like a pain in the ass.
知道你该怎么办吗
You know what you should do?
你该学学那些什么都不在乎的家伙
You should take a page from those carefree bastards
去冲个浪  换换脑子
and you should catch a wave, huh? Clear your mind.
乔能给你介绍个好教练
Joe's got a great instructor down your way.
她可棒了
She's, uh-- she's amazing.
知道吗  她叫
And guess what, her name--
莎蒂
it's, uh-- her name is Sandy.
-莎蒂  -是吧  乔
- Sandy. - Right, Joe.
好啊  很想见见她
That's good. Love to meet her.
我知道你们是想哄我
Look, I know I'm being managed here.
这酒的味道不错  但也冲不走
Glenfiddich goes down nice, but it doesn't wipe away
警察那通电话给我的难受
the taste of that phone call from those cops.
托弗还是个孩子  我们不让孩子胡闹
Topher's still a teenager. We don't let our boy run wild.
卡尔  我听说
Cal, I was very troubled
你儿子的事后十分不安
when I heard what happened to your son.
我完全不知道我家里有未成年人
I had no idea there were minors in my home
和毒品
or narcotics,
我绝不会赞成那种事的
and in no universe would I approve of that.
好吧
All right.
你人似乎不错
You seem like a decent man.
不像弗里斯科的疯子
Not some 'Frisco nutjob.
我会向我家领导  就是我那口子好好交待
I'll submit a detailed report to the big boss, I.E., my wife,
应该就没事了
and, uh, that should clear things up.
不过最好别跟她提莎蒂
Might not mention Sandy to her, though.
穿潜水衣的姑娘最美了  是吧
Nothing like a girl in a wet suit, am I right?
可不是  但我更喜欢比基尼
You sure are. Although, I prefer a bikini.
嗯
Yeah.
旧金山的一些生意伙伴
Some of our business associates in SF,
挺滑稽的  懂吗
they're a little funny, if you catch my drift.
握手无力
Soft handshakes.
或许我们走运
Hell, maybe we'll get lucky
那些死基佬会染上那种特别的流感
and all the faggots will catch that special flu that's going around.
只要我儿子不染上就行
As long as my son stays away from it.
反正有的是时间管教他
But, uh, got plenty of time to whip him into shape.
我说了  他还小
Like I said, he's still a kid.
好了  先生们  差不多了
All right, gentlemen, it's that time.
好的  先生
All right. Yes, sir.
小心点
Hey, watch it, man.
我觉得你不用担心你儿子
Do you know, I wouldn't worry about your son.
等他远离了你  就会找到自己的道路
He'll find his path when he gets away from you.
但我替你老婆难过
But I feel sorry for your wife.
她不得不躺在那里忍受你
She has to lie there taking it,
心里想着  自己是造了什么孽
wondering what the hell she did
要闻你嘴里的恶臭
to have your stinking breath in her face.
等等  或许我错了
Or, wait, maybe I was wrong.
或许闻你口臭的不是你家领导
Maybe the big boss isn't the one taking it.
老天啊  乔
Jesus Christ, Joe.
那孙子都被我们搞定了  你非得...
We had the son of a bitch locked and you had to--
非得怎么
Had to what?
我们是向政府卖安全软件的
We sell security software to the government.
等等  别这样
Wait. Come on,
昨晚跟你聊天很开心
It was great hanging out with you last night.
-我能...  -嗯
- Can I just-- - Uh, yeah.
好啊
Sure.
好
Cool.
你继续工作吧
I'll let you get back to work.
听说你俩昨晚好好谈了谈
I heard you two had a good conversation last night.
是啊
Uh, yeah.
我决定保留跳蚤市场原有的代码
I decided to, uh, keep the SwapMeet code as it is
将部分穆特尼代码转为C++好连接界面
and translate some of Mutiny into C++ to bridge the interface.
真的  那太好了
Really? That's great.
他们会激动坏的
The guys are gonna be thrilled.
而且  我觉得我们该解雇他们
And I think we should fire them.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
你有合理的理由可以跟黛安交待吗
Do you have an actual, you know, reason we can give Diane,
因为她得为此买单
since she's the one who's gonna have to pay for it?
有
Yes.
我们不需要他们
We don't need them.
今晚吃饭
Well, the dinner is tonight.
如果你真想解雇他们
If you really want to fire the guys,
你自己跟黛安说去吧
then you can tell Diane yourself.
不  他们有三人玩的《雪人山任务》
Oh, no! They have three-player "Yeti Mountain Mission"?
比一场
Race!
不不  别玩电玩
No, no, no, no, no. No video games.
我们是来团建的
We're here to coalesce as a group.
-什么  -按"搞"度排队
- What? - So line up by "Heighth."
-什么  -"搞"度
- What? - "Heighth"?
高度  按高度排队  你们的身高
Height. Line up by height. How tall you are.
高度
Height.
你站最后
So you're gonna be at the end.
你站那边最后
You're at this end over here.
-头发也算高度吗  -是的
- Hey, does hair count? - Yes, hair counts.
去那边
Down here at the end.
阿基  你站中间  莱夫  那边
Arki, you're in the center. Lev, you're there.
神童  最后面
Wonderboy, down at the end.
快点  各位
Come on, guys.
好了  神童
Yeah, Wonderboy.
好了  盟军司令部命令你们
All right, you've been ordered by Allied Command
选12名普通军事犯
to select 12 general prisoners...
-我是无辜的  -他们被军事法庭判刑
- I'm innocent. - ...convicted by courts-martial
即将被判死刑  或服很长的刑期
and sentenced to be executed or serve lengthy prison terms
罪名是杀人  抢劫
for murder, robbery,
打将军的耳朵
striking a general in the ear,
以及其他暴力犯罪行为
and other crimes of violence.
你要带他们深入敌后
And you will deliver them behind enemy lines
进入法国  执行破坏任务
in France to undertake a mission of sabotage
该任务或许能改变战争结果
that could change the course of the war.
好吧  李·马文
Okay, Lee Marvin,
可那部电影里大部分人最后不是死了吗
but don't most of the guys in that movie eat it?
最后非常惨
By the end, is it more like the "Dirty Deuce"?
我叫你知道什么叫惨  博迪
I'll show you a Dirty Deuce, Bodie.
这是隐喻
It's a metaphor.
其实  应该叫寓言
Actually, it's more of an allegory.
别那么激动  蓝妹妹
Uh, pipe down, Smurfette.
寓言就是一种隐喻
An allegory is a metaphor.
去你妹  精子
F you, semen.
精子  她喊我精子吗
Semen? Did she just call me semen?
下场战役开始了
It's time for the next battle!
天呐
God.
各位玩家  跟我来熟悉一下
Players, follow me for instruction
公平比赛的规则
in the rules of honorable play.
你得小点声
You need to turn down your toys.
走吧  各位  展现一下你们的本事
Come on, guys. Let's see a little bit of that Apache know-how.
掩护我  掩护我
Cover me, cover me!
他在那儿
There he is, there he is!
-小心  大块头  -该死
- Buckle up, big man. - Shit!
各位  别傻站着  反击啊
Guys, don't just stand around. Fight back!
-我没子弹了  我完了  -去你的
- I'm out, I'm done. - Screw you, asshole.
绿队  集合
Green team, gather round, gather round.
好了  集中精神
All right, look, focus, okay?
守住基地  互相掩护
Guard the base. Get each other's backs, all right?
这东西好使吗
Is this thing even on?
博迪  趴下  你要被打中的
Bodie, get down. You're in the line of fire!
神童  别吃了
Wonderboy, get that out of your mouth.
拜托  专心点
Come on, man, get your head in the game.
各位  看啊
Hey, guys, check it out.
如果把这玩意遮住  就不会被打中了
If you just cover this thing, you can't get hit.
肯定有办法解除整个系统
There must be a way to disengage the entire system.
你们一群娘炮
What a bunch of pussies.
这是性别歧视
That's sexist.
-他是你队友  -去你妈  死屌
- He's on our team! - F off, you big D.
天呐  停下
Oh, my God, stop!
我们都要死了
We're all gonna die!
审判日到了  各位罪人
It's Judgment Day, sinners!
躲过一击
Dodged a shot.
BGM: Goodnight, Saigon
我们上吧
Let's do this!
好诶
Yeah!
先生  先生  你被取消资格了
Sir! Sir! You are officially disqualified.
什么
What?!
绿队  绿队  绿队
Green! Green! Green!
我们绝对相信
We feel 100% confident.
只要任务指派明确
If we're properly assigned,
我们三周就能完成
we can get this whole thing out the door in three weeks.
三周
Three weeks?
这比我们想的要快得多  是吧
That's much sooner than we expected, right?
我真希望...
Oh, I just wish--
算了  她不会来了
Let it go. She's not coming.
我以为你俩都谈好了
I thought you two had a good conversation.
是啊  我也以为
Yeah, I thought so, too.
我们非常尊敬卡梅
We have so much respect for Cam
和你们共同建立的一切
and what you guys have built together.
听上去很好
It sounds nice and all,
但关键问题是  你们能和她配合吗
but the real question is can you work with her?
-绝对的  -当然了
- Definitely. - Of course.
我们是觉得她没法跟我们配合
We just get the feeling she can't work with us.
知道吗
You know?
可以点餐了吗
Are we ready to go ahead and order?
对不起
I'm sorry.
不怪你
It's not your fault.
买单
Can we have the check, please?
我觉得如果卡梅不想跟他们合作
I just think if Cam doesn't want to work with the guys,
她该有勇气当面处理
she should have the courage to deal with it face-to-face.
我知道
No, I know.
我是想让她跟你说的
Look, I wanted her to tell you,
但既然她没来
but since she's not here...
卡梅想解雇道格和克雷格
Cam wants to fire Doug and Craig.
是吗  这是大事
Really? That's big.
是啊
Yeah.
你也同意吗
Do you agree with her?
她是我的合伙人
Well, I-- she's my partner.
我个人觉得他们是很好的人才
Personally, I think these guys are a big asset.
但你和卡梅伦的关系才是最重要的
But your relationship with Cameron is the most important thing.
那才是我的投资对象
That's what I'm investing in.
如果无法跟道格和克雷格合作下去
If working with Doug and Craig is untenable,
穆特尼可以提前付清他们的钱  让他们走人
Mutiny can pay their earn-out early and send 'em home.
但你才说他们是重要人才
But you just said that they're a big asset.
我当然不会乐意
I wouldn't be happy about it,
但强扭的瓜不甜
but it's better than forcing something toxic.
我只是希望问题是真出在他们身上
I just hope it's the guys who are the problem.
团建得怎么样了
So, how's the team-building coming?
还挺有成效
Well, surprisingly productive.
但由于我争议性的军事策略
Although I've been banned from future competition
被禁止再来参赛了
due to my controversial military tactics.
你可以过去  他们还在呢
You can get out there. They're still there.
挺好玩的
It's stupid fun.
不了  我过来是因为
No, I just came by 'cause I--
我说过会来
well, 'cause I said I would.
瞧瞧你  好和气先生
Well, look at you, Mr. Nice Guy.
好和气先生
Mr. Nice Guy?
当年在卡迪夫  你是销售部高级副总裁
Back at Cardiff, you were the heavy SVP of Sales.
那些上百万的客户
All those multimillion-dollar accounts,
大家都怕死你了
everybody was scared shitless of you.
我也是
You know, including myself.
但现在
But now...
现在怎么了
Now what?
我就是说  做老板听上去很不错
Look, I just mean, you know, being the boss sounds good,
但这样更好
but this is better.
不用负多少责  乐趣无穷
There's minimal responsibility, maximum fun.
对了  你总跟大家讲的那个故事是什么来着
Which reminds me, what's that story you keep telling the guys?
-那个什么...  -那个没意思了
- Something about... - That thing's outta gas.
博斯
Bos!
-你真该看到的  -你绝不会相信的
- You should've seen it. - Oh, man, you're not gonna believe it.
戈登像神风队队员一样
Gordon went full-on kamikaze.
他差点把那人干死
He practically murdered the guy.
起初感觉挺没劲
It seemed totally lame at first,
不过还真挺有意思的
but it was actually pretty awesome.
是啊  她都喜欢
Yeah, even she liked it.
你下轮该跟我们一起玩
You should play the next round, man.
-你肯定打得好  -不了
- You would shred this course. - No.
来嘛
Come on. Come on.
博斯  博斯
Bos! Bos! Bos!
不了
No, I'm good.
真不了
I said I'm good!
再去玩一轮吧
Go have another round.
去吧  你们那么喜欢
Get on in there. You guys enjoy it.
好吧
Okay, yeah.
卡梅
Cam.
几点了
What time is it?
很晚了  你没去吃晚饭
It's late. You missed the dinner.
天呐  唐娜  真抱歉
Oh, my God, Donna, I'm sorry.
天呐  我不知道...
Jesus, I-- I don't know...
我想去的  我打算去的
I meant to be there. I planned to be there.
我不知道是怎么了
I don't know what happened.
你工作太辛苦了  就是这样
You're overworked, that's what happened.
你累坏了
You're exhausted.
晚饭吃得怎么样
Um, how was the dinner?
挺好
Fine.
道格挺能忍的
Doug sucked up a lot.
天呐  我烦死那人了
God, I hate that guy.
我知道  但克雷格还好
I know. But Craig's okay.
是啊
Yeah.
他们走后
After they left,
我跟黛安说了你想解雇他们
I told Diane you want to fire them.
怎么样
And?
她说不行
She said no.
什么意思  她说不行
What do you mean, she said no?
他们是协议的一部分
They're a part of the deal.
他们是重要人才
They're an important asset
我们只能想办法跟他们合作
and we have to find a way to make it work.
什么
What?
她不是我们这边的吗
I thought she was on our side.
她觉得这样对公司更好
She feels it's what's best for the company.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  多谢你去问  我很感激
Okay, well, thank you for asking. I really appreciate it.
嗯
Yeah.
-回家见  -嗯
- I'll see you at home. - Yeah.
有人吗
Hello?
我不介意晚上工作  但你的电话有点吓到我了
I'm cool to work at night, but your call kind of freaked me out.
我们今天失去了通用原子
We lost General Atomics today.
他们是我们37%的年收入
They represent 37% of our annual billing.
怎么回事
What happened?
我拿他们换了更有价值的东西
I traded them for something more valuable.
这是什么
What's this?
阿帕网的登录凭证
The log-in credentials for the ARPANET,
那是国防部的包交换网络
the Department of Defense packet-switching network.
我通过通用原子得到的信息
I secured the information through General Atomics.
赶在我的登录凭证失效前
I want you to look into it before they flag
你好好看看
that my credentials still work.
好  但阿帕网不是新东西
Okay, but, you know, the ARPANET isn't new tech.
挺旧的了  又不是导弹代码
It's sort of rusty. It's not like missile codes.
或消防飞机图纸
Or fire plane blueprints.
这没什么意思
This is-- this is mundane stuff.
我知道  是古董了
I do know that. It's antiquated.
所以它需要升级
And that means it's ripe for an upgrade.
我该做什么
So what should I do?
你进去  看个明白
I need you to go into it, map it,
帮我想出接下来该怎么做
and help me figure out what's next.
为什么
Why?
-先玩这个  -有两个控制器
- Play after this. - There's two controllers, though.
等我玩完前十的
Play after I finish the best out of 10.
你是个《打鸭子》白痴天才啊
Man, you're like some kind of "Duck Hunt" Savant.
难道我在其他方面就不行吗
Does that mean I'm totally deficient in other areas?
《打鸭子》天才  但不会团队合作
Like "Duck Hunt" Savant, but bad team player.
拜托
Come on.
跟那俩...
So how's it going with...
混蛋和二货处得咋样了
...Dick und Doof?
混蛋和二货
Dick und Doof?
我的德裔祖父就这么喊劳莱和哈代[喜剧组合]
That's what my German grandfather called Laurel and Hardy.
意思大概是"胖子和笨蛋"
Loosely translates to "Chubby and Dumb."
贴切  道格是混蛋
Well, that's perfect, 'cause Doug's the Dick...
克雷格是个二货
Und Craig ist Doof.
-是啊  -是啊
- Ja. - Ja.
无所谓了
Oh, whatever, though.
看来我只能想办法合作了
I guess I'm gonna have to make it work.
你现在成了和事老
All right, hope you haven't lost your edge
希望水平没下去
now that you're a peacemaker.
要汽水吗
Uh, oh, do you want a soda?
-好啊  -嗯
- Yeah, sure. - Yeah?
老天
Jesus!
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
我想跟你说件事
You know, I wanted to tell you something.
我在想  你想留多久都行
I've been thinking, and you should stay here as long as you want.
找房子不急的
You can take your time finding a place.
谢谢  太棒了
Oh, thanks. Yes!
好了  给你了
All right, all you.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
你什么时候知道自己要失去卡迪夫的
When did you know you were losing Cardiff?